<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Explainers on Zach Wong</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/explainers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Explainers on Zach Wong</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>content © 2025 zach wong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/explainers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A lightweight introduction to TEEs and how they’re being used today</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-lightweight-introduction-to-tees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-lightweight-introduction-to-tees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting areas of blockchain innovation is the use of “TEEs” to introduce &lt;em&gt;verifiability&lt;/em&gt; in important systems. A “TEE” is a special kind of computer that has an embedded private key. The computer can use the private key to make verifiable attestations about its behavior.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As discussed prior in this blog (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://paragraph.com/@mud2monarch/disaggregating-decentralization&#34;&gt;Gyges Lydias: Disaggregating Decentralization&lt;/a&gt;), verifiability is one of the key goods provided by decentralization. In this case, even though a TEE may be run by a single party, it still provides valuable user protections worth pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visa&#39;s strategic opportunity to win a world of blockchain payments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/visa-opportunity-blockchain-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/visa-opportunity-blockchain-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One dominant narrative of blockchain technology is that it will disintermediate traditional financial services, leading to the demise of traditional firms. While I agree with the premise, I disagree with the conclusion. Traditional firms are very well-positioned to take market share from their current competitors and dominate the next two decades of financial services. In this article, I conduct a SWOT analysis for Visa and describe the strategic opportunity for the payments network in a world where public blockchains are ubiquitously adopted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New developments in crypto payments policy, Consensus 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-developments-in-crypto-payments-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-developments-in-crypto-payments-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most important regulatory news from Consensus 2023 will likely go uncovered. In an interview announcing a new product at Consensus, PayPal SVP Jose Fernandez da Ponte said that PayPal currently covers $50,000 of consumer liability for crypto transfers, which is in line with the requirements of the CFPB’s Regulation E.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enforcing Reg E for crypto payments has always been the most natural way for the CFPB to start regulating the crypto market, but the agency has to this date declined to ever do so (to my knowledge). Therefore, I’m always on the lookout for new developments in crypto-Reg E. PayPal’s voluntary semi-compliance is an important development in the state of crypto consumer payments regulation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography to Cryptocurrency: Lessons on Privacy and Policy from Steven Levy’s “Crypto”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crypto-lessons-from-levy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crypto-lessons-from-levy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The practice (of preserving anonymity) was crucial in the formation of the United States itself, and was arguably as American as apple pie. As cypherpunk historians loved to point out, the model for the Ender’s Game debate may have been the Federalist Papers, with parts written by James Madison, John Jay, and Alexander Hamilton but published under the pseudonym Publius. And when Thomas Paine wrote Common Sense, he originally signed it “An Englishman.” As the Supreme Court would note, “Anonymous pamphlets, leaflets, brochures, and even books have played an important role in the progress of mankind,” a role the Court has sustained in consistent ruling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My column in Bitcoin Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bitcoin-magazine-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bitcoin-magazine-column/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following tweets on the subject, I was invited to write the following column for Bitcoin Magazine. I think it’s important to explain DC goings-on to cryptonative audiences, so I accepted the invitation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can read the article on Bitcoin Magazine&amp;rsquo;s main site &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitcoinmagazine.com/culture/us-treasury-bitcoin-not-illicit?source=post_page-----b11ed306fa73---------------------------------------&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve republished the piece (with my original title, syntax, and conventions) below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are my independent thoughts and do not necessarily represent the views of my employer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitcoins-paltry-use-for-illicit-activity-is-now-indisputable&#34;&gt;Bitcoin’s Paltry Use for Illicit Activity is now Indisputable&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s time to take “illicit activity” off the FUD dice. Earlier this month, the US Treasury Department published reports that said, definitively, the use of bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies for illicit activity is far outstripped by the use of traditional assets. Critics can no longer credibly present the specter of illicit activity to beat back bitcoin; the foremost experts in the world say it is not a major threat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Galaxy Far, Far Away: The Cryptonative’s Guide to US Financial Regulators</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/galaxy-far-far-away-regulators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/galaxy-far-far-away-regulators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;img-caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2022/galaxy_imageONE.webp&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;A New Hope: Satoshi Nakamoto, center, surveys the financial services landscape in 2008. He sees central banks debasing the currency, banks lending money in waves of credit bubbles, and massive overhead costs that make micropayments impossible. He creates Bitcoin, a 3720-to-1 longshot to start a neutral, distributed monetary system with no single point of failure.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A New Hope&lt;/strong&gt;: Satoshi Nakamoto, center, surveys the financial services landscape in 2008. He sees central banks debasing the currency, banks lending money in waves of credit bubbles, and massive overhead costs that make micropayments impossible. He creates Bitcoin, a 3720-to-1 longshot to start a neutral, distributed monetary system with no single point of failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing and contrasting PayPal balances with USDC from first principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/paypal-balances-usdc-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/paypal-balances-usdc-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For if the people are not equal, they will not have equal things. Rather, from this arises fights and accusations, either when people who are equal have or are distributed unequal things, or when people who are unequal have or are distributed equal things…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nicomachean Ethics&lt;/em&gt;, 1131a, trans. Bartlett and Collins&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since stablecoins have started to receive scrutiny by US federal regulators, it’s been increasingly popular to compare them to other types of nonbank digital dollars such as PayPal, Cash App, or Venmo balances. This comparison makes intuitive sense because (centralized) stablecoins are a dollar-denominated corporate liability that can be used on a proprietary payments network. If the products are very similar, there exists a nice template for regulation, provided a “like for like” standard is applied. In this post, I compare and contrast PayPal balances with USDC and provide preliminary thoughts on regulatory steps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fed&#39;s CBDC Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fed-cbdc-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fed-cbdc-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;img-caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2022/cbdc_dolla_on_blockchain.webp&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;A CBDC is a government-issued dollar on a blockchain.&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;A CBDC is a government-issued dollar on a blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Earlier today, the Federal Reserve Board released its much-anticipated &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.federalreserve.gov/publications/money-and-payments-discussion-paper.htm&#34;&gt;discussion paper&lt;/a&gt; on central bank digital currency. To be frank, little was new: Chair Powell &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/22/business/jerome-powell-says-the-fed-wont-issue-a-digital-currency-without-congressional-approval.html&#34;&gt;has already said&lt;/a&gt; that the Fed will not develop or deploy a US CBDC without congressional approval. And Fed staff and governors &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/waller20210805a.htm&#34;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/quarles20210628a.htm&#34;&gt;already&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://libertystreeteconomics.newyorkfed.org/2021/04/hey-economist-whats-the-case-for-central-bank-digital-currencies/&#34;&gt;done&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/files/brainard20210524a.pdf&#34;&gt;a good job&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/notes/feds-notes/preconditions-for-a-general-purpose-central-bank-digital-currency-20210224.htm&#34;&gt;explaining&lt;/a&gt; some of the pros, cons, and potential for a US CBDC. Perhaps the most novel announcement was a concrete outline of the Fed’s vision for a CBDC, which it said would most effectively be “privacy-protected, intermediated, widely transferable, and identity-verified.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happens to policy proposals, anyways?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-happens-to-policy-proposals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-happens-to-policy-proposals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;img-caption&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2021/proposals_imageONE.webp&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;A crypto user contemplates a future in which he and his frens have shirked informed, productive engagement with policymakers, who then pass legislation and regulations that disfavor crypto.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;A crypto user contemplates a future in which he and his frens have shirked informed, productive engagement with policymakers, who then pass legislation and regulations that disfavor crypto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#39;callout callout-custom&#39; style=&#39;background-color: transparent; border: 3px solid #d340e0;&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    👀 &lt;u&gt;Note June 2024&lt;/u&gt;&#xA;    &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;    I wrote this pseudonymously when I worked at the CFPB, hence some of the disclaimers that may seem weird now (which were required by my agreement with my agency’s ethics office). Everything here still reflects my views though!.&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several prominent crypto firms recently released proposals for how the US government should regulate cryptocurrencies and other related products. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; While the proposals created buzz on Twitter and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/new-approach-regulating-crypto-bitcoin-coinbase-armstrong-digital-asset-policy-proposal-11634226117&#34;&gt;traditional media&lt;/a&gt;, I think it’s unclear to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jeffjohnroberts/status/1460639126869450756?s=20&#34;&gt;most people&lt;/a&gt; — to put it generously — what the actual effect of such policy proposals will be. In this post, I hope to answer this question and demystify the US federal policymaking process from the perspective of an insider.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
