<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence on Zach Wong</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence on Zach Wong</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>content © 2025 zach wong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hackathon project: extracting BigQuery table schemas for use with an LLM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uni-schema-tool-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uni-schema-tool-demo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Uniswap Labs’ biannual onsites, we dedicate most of the week to a company hackathon. It’s a time to think creatively, work on personal projects related to work, and collaborate with others. This time around, I wrote a short script to gather and coalesce BigQuery table schemas into a text document for use with an LLM. An executable, source code, and a usage guide are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mud2monarch/personal-projects/tree/main/uni-schema&#34;&gt;my Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem-to-solve&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem to solve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of my work, I regularly use LLMs to help with data queries. We have a broad set of high-quality onchain and offchain data stored in Google BigQuery, and I write SQL to access and transform the data into actionable insights. LLMs — e.g., Claude, ChatGPT — are very helpful for accelerating that work because they help me quickly iterate on my code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: How to learn anything in the world using generative AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tutorial-learn-generative-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tutorial-learn-generative-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are in a golden age of learning enabled by generative AI. Yet I am constantly stunned by how few people are using generative AI to learn new things. In the below video, I explain how to use GPT-4 as a &lt;em&gt;teacher&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By teaching myself what a tensor is, what the role of math is in modern machine learning, and how to create a class in Python, I hope to show you how you can use generative AI to learn anything in the world. I explain my prompts, what I’m thinking about, how to control hallucinations, and other small tips for how to use generative AI to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
