<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Zach Wong</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Zach Wong</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>content © 2025 zach wong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A short exploration of Solana MEV data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/solana-mev-exploration-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/solana-mev-exploration-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tryghost.xyz/graph&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; is a company that allows developers to create custom blockchain indexes using Solidity. They &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/0xGhostLogs/status/1843770831245050159&#34;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; a dataset that contains 1.06m Solana transactions from September 2024 that they identified as atomic arbitrage* transactions containing SOL/WSOL. This article quickly analyzes that dataset. Thanks to Ghost for making this available!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#39;callout callout-custom&#39; style=&#39;background-color: transparent; border: 3px solid #8C5DA7;&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    🕵️ &lt;u&gt;&amp;#34;Atomic Arbitrage&amp;#34;&lt;/u&gt;&#xA;    &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;    Atomic arbitrage is a type of arbitrage that takes place within a single set of transactions. For example, someone may notice that the SOL &amp;lt;&amp;gt; USDC and USDC &amp;lt;&amp;gt; USDT and USDT &amp;lt;&amp;gt; SOL prices provide an arbitrage opportunity, and closes it in a single block/slot. This would NOT include CEX-DEX arbitrage, which does not/cannot occur atomically.&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The notebook for this article is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mud2monarch/personal-projects/blob/main/Solana_atomic_arbs/Solana_atomic_arbs.ipynb&#34;&gt;my Github.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration: Gas fees and validator payments on Ethereum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gas-fees-validator-payments-eth-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gas-fees-validator-payments-eth-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ethereum validator revenue &lt;a href=&#34;https://eth2book.info/capella/part2/incentives/#p_4&#34;&gt;consists of three things&lt;/a&gt;: native protocol issuance, priority fees, and MEV. Native protocol issuance is well-understood and &lt;a href=&#34;https://eth2book.info/capella/part2/incentives/issuance/&#34;&gt;scales with respect&lt;/a&gt; to the square root of the number of validators. From what I can find, priority fees are less well-understood, and MEV even less so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding validator revenue is important because a number of exciting financial products are being built on top of validator yield. Most straightforwardly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.compassft.com/indice/styeth/&#34;&gt;Compass-ft’s STYETH index&lt;/a&gt; and the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://coinfund.io/cesr/&#34;&gt;Compound Ether Staking Rate&lt;/a&gt; (“CESR,” pronounced like the former Roman dictator), created by CoinFund and published by CoinDesk Indices, measure historical ETH validator yield. When it comes to tradeable products, blockspace futures from &lt;a href=&#34;https://alkimiya.io/documentation/&#34;&gt;Alkimiya&lt;/a&gt; are a related product where the price of a future (currently called a Silica) should vary with ETH validator yield.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
